(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
The concert will be starting soon.
開演までしばらくお待ちください
#hololivefesEXPO24_DAY2
Please wait a moment for the performance to begin.
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To all visitors
演出の都合上
照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
Attention
For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
オフィシャルグッズ
Official Goods
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sales Period
バンダイ
Bandai
バンダイ・BANDAI SPIRITSより
From Bandai and Bandai Spirits,
EXPO会場でも展示中の商品をご紹介！
introducing items currently on display at the EXPO venue!
...くじなど、たくさんの商品が発売いたします。
...lotteries and more, many items will be released.
一番くじ ホロライブ アートアクリルコレクション
2024年5月18日(土)より順次発売予定
Ichiban Kuji Hololive Art Acrylic Collection
Scheduled for release starting May 18, 2024 (Sat)
バンダイブース、バンダイスピリッツブースでは、会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
At the Bandai and Bandai Spirits booths, venue-exclusive items are being distributed for free!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンももらえる！
On Premium Bandai, you can also get coupons that can be used immediately!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも、青春しよう！
Let's enjoy our youth on the stage of Weiß Schwarz too!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション サマーコレクション！
Premium Booster: hololive production Summer Collection!
3月22日金曜日発売！
Released on Friday, March 22nd!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
ホロスターズが、ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
HOLOSTARS makes their debut in Weiß Schwarz Blau!
ようこそ、カードゲームの舞台へ！
Welcome to the card game stage!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウ スタートデッキ&ブースターパック ホロスターズ、好評発売中！
Weiß Schwarz Blau Start Deck & Booster Pack: HOLOSTARS, now on sale!
ブシロード！
Bushiroad!
ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが、新衣装になって再登場！
Hololive members' Nendoroids are back in their new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどもお楽しみに！
Look forward to new Nendoroids too!
グッドスマイルカンパニー！
Good Smile Company!
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設に、続々登場！
From FuRyu, 'Hololive' prizes are arriving one after another at amusement facilities nationwide!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
Planned to feature all domestic Hololive members in the future!
フリュー！
FuRyu!
ReGLOSS 2nd Single「シンメトリー」
Digital Release 2024.03.24(SUN) 0:00
ReGLOSS 2nd Single "Symmetry"
Digital Release 2024.03.24 (SUN) 0:00
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Attention: To all visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Vocal cheering is OK.
Attention For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is ok.
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes.
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sale Period
バンダイ
Bandai
バンダイスピリッツより、EXPO会場でも展示中の商品をご紹介！
From Bandai Spirits, we're introducing products currently on display at the EXPO venue!
ウエハースや...
Wafers and...
ドンジャラNEOやマイク、ステッキなどたくさんの商品が発売いたします。
Donjara NEO, microphones, sticks, and many other products will be released.
バンダイブース、バンダイスピリッツブースでは、会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
At the Bandai and Bandai Spirits booths, venue-exclusive goods are also being distributed for free!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンももらえる！
On P-Bandai, you can also get coupons that can be used immediately!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも青春しよう！
Let's enjoy our youth on the stage of Weiß Schwarz too!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション Summer Collection 3月22日発売！
Premium Booster Hololive Production Summer Collection, on sale March 22nd!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
ホロスターズがヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
HOLOSTARS makes their appearance in Weiß Schwarz Blau!
ようこそ、カードゲームの舞台へ。
Welcome to the stage of card games.
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウ スタートデッキ＆ブースターパック『ホロスターズ』好評発売中！
Weiß Schwarz Blau Start Deck & Booster Pack 'HOLOSTARS' is now on sale!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024開催を記念して...
To commemorate the holding of hololive SUPER EXPO 2024...
ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが新衣装になって再登場！
Nendoroids of hololive members are back in their new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどもお楽しみに！
Please look forward to the new Nendoroids as well!
フリューから『ホロライブ』プライズが全国アミューズメント施設に...
Hololive prizes from FuRyu are coming to amusement facilities nationwide...
2024年7月以降に続々登場！
Appearing one after another starting from July 2024!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
We plan to roll out all domestic hololive members in the future!
フリュー
FuRyu
a-
推しの曲、めーっちゃいいね！
My oshi's song is sooo good!
みるハコちゃーん！
Miruhako-chan!
みるハコなら、臨場感たっぷりで推しのコンテンツが楽しめる！
With Miruhako, you can enjoy your favorite contents with a great sense of presence!
みるハコ最高！
Miruhako is the best!
お外も増やそう、みるハコ。
Let's increase the fun outdoors too, Miruhako.
大好きを込めて
With all my love
君に届ける
Sending it to you
この想い全部
All these feelings
受け取ってね
Please receive them
HoneyWorks stage
Official Hashtag #hololivefesEXPO24_DAY2 The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To Visitors
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援 OK です
Cheering loudly is OK.
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment オフィシャルグッズ
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment Official Goods
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Goods Sales Period
当日販売
Same-day Sales
事後通販
Post-event mail order
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
hololive 5th fes. を応援しています！
I'm supporting hololive 5th fes.!
最高のパフォーマンスが見られるのを楽しみにしてます！
I'm looking forward to seeing the best performance!
Always worth flying in to see our shark idol shine!
This is going to be amazing!
5th fes おめでとうございます！
Congratulations on the 5th fes.!
hololive 5th fes. 楽しみにしてました！！
I've been looking forward to hololive 5th fes.!!
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
演出の都合上 照明の点滅にご注意ください
声出し応援 OK です
Attention: To all visitors. Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Vocal cheering is allowed.
Attention For Visitors
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
Cheering loudly is ok.
Attention For Visitors: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance. Cheering loudly is ok.
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment オフィシャルグッズ
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment Official Merchandise
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024 & hololive 5th fes.
オフィシャルグッズ販売期間
Official Merchandise Sales Period
沙花叉結婚しよっ？
Sakamata, will you marry me?
角巻 SDS
Tsunomaki SDS
Peko 最強
Peko is the strongest
ラミィ命
Lamy is my life
沙花叉をあまやかすな！
Don't spoil Sakamata!
シシロン大好きー！
I love Shishiron!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm Gonna Give You Fan Service
ときのそら
Tokino Sora
白上フブキ
Shirakami Fubuki
夏色まつり
Natsuiro Matsuri
紫咲シオン
Murasaki Shion
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
AZKi
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
さくらみこ
Sakura Miko
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
星街すいせい
Hoshimachi Suisei
兎田ぺこら
Usada Pekora
不知火フレア
Shiranui Flare
白銀ノエル
Shirogane Noel
宝鐘マリン
Houshou Marine
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
角巻わため
Tsunomaki Watame
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna
雪花ラミィ
Yukihana Lamy
桃鈴ねね
Momosuzu Nene
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
ラプラス・ダークネス
La+ Darknesss
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
博衣こより
Hakui Koyori
沙花叉クロヱ
Sakamata Chloe
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
ムーナ・ホシノヴァ
Moona Hoshinova
クレイジー・オリー
Kureiji Ollie
アーニャ・メルフィッサ
Anya Melfissa
こぼ・かなえる
Kobo Kanaeru
小鳥遊キアラ
Takanashi Kiara
がうる・ぐら
Gawr Gura
ハコス・ベールズ
Hakos Baelz
hololive 5th fes. Capture the Moment
hololive production × HoneyWorks
好きになって もっと
Love me even more
私を見て もっと
Look at me even more
恩返しは
In return for your support
愛のこもった投げキッスで
With a loving blowing kiss
気のせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not your imagination, our eyes are meeting
ハート作って
Make a heart
恋しちゃってください
And please fall in love with me
ねだること 何でもします
I'll do anything you ask of me
エナジー増して
With increased energy
体当たり上等
Ready for a head-on collision
あざとさで見つけた 味の濃い目
A strong flavor found through cuteness
不貞腐れ 誰より勝ってるし
I'm better at being spiteful than anyone
でも大丈夫 ここに立てば
But it's okay, if I stand here
みんなが見える
I can see everyone
いくよー！
Here we go!
好きになって もっと
Love me even more
私を見て もっと
Look at me even more
恩返しは
In return for your support
愛のこもった投げキッスで
With a loving blowing kiss
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you even more
夢を見せる もっと
I'll show you more dreams
楽しんでって
Please enjoy yourself
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
A special night filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you some fan service
みんな声出して！
Everyone, let me hear your voices!
お手紙も書いてください
Please write me letters too
何度も読んで 宝物にします
I'll read them over and over and treasure them
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
A scandal is still too early for me
裏切りません 宣言しときます
I won't betray you, I'm declaring it now
嫉妬や嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment
ふざけた実力で勝ってやる
I'll win with my ridiculous skills
だからやめない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
So I won't stop, I'm a sore loser, I am here
いくよー！
Here we go!
拳上げて もっと
Raise your fists even more
汗をかいて もっと
Sweat even more
恩返しは
In return for your support
愛のこもったホロライブで
With a Hololive filled with love
虜にする もっと
I'll captivate you even more
まだまだ行け！ もっと
Keep going! Even more!
受け止めてね
Please accept it
愛のこもったわがままソング
A selfish song filled with love
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you some fan service
終わりが近づく 寂しいね
The end is approaching, it's sad, isn't it?
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying
次も 次も また会えるよね 約束！
Next time, and the time after that, we'll meet again, right? Promise!
みんな、大好きだよー！
Everyone, I love you!
優しさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness
心無い誰かの言葉さえも
And even the heartless words of someone else
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強くなろう
I need them, I need them, let's become strong
好きにさせて
Make you love me
もっと
more
楽しんじゃえ
Let's have fun
もっと
more
忘れないで
Don't forget
特別な日になりますように
I hope this becomes a special day
共に歌おう　ずっと
Let's sing together forever
共に歩もう　ずっと
Let's walk together forever
合言葉は
The watchword is
とびっきりのL-O-V-E
The very best L-O-V-E
好きになって　もっと
Love me more
私を見て　もっと
Look at me more
恩返しは
My way of giving back is
愛のこもった投げキッスで
with a blow-kiss full of love
虜にする　もっと
I'll captivate you more
夢を見せる　もっと
I'll show you more dreams
楽しんでて
Keep having fun
愛のこもったスペシャルナイト
A special night full of love
感謝しちゃうんだ
I'm so grateful
ありがとう！
Thank you!
このあとももっともっと私たちのこと好きにさせちゃうから
We'll make you love us even more after this!
最後まで盛り上がってけー！
Let's keep the energy up until the end!
皆さーん！着席！
Everyone! Take your seats!
一回座りましょう！
Let's sit down for a moment!
一回座ってください！
Please sit down for a moment!
よしよしよし、いいですよ、いいですよ。
Good, good, good, that's it, that's it.
いいお返事ですよ。
What a good response.
さあ皆さん、座りましたかね？
Now then, is everyone seated?
今日はホロハニフェスですからね。
Today is the Holo-Honey fest, after all.
じゃあ行きますよ。
Alright, here we go.
全校生徒、起立！
All students, stand up!
気を付け！
Attention!
礼！
Bow!
先生、おはようございます！
Good morning, Teacher!
おはよう。
Good morning.
あ、フブキちゃん。
Oh, Fubuki-chan.
よくできた、よくできた。座れ座れ。
Well done, well done. Sit down, sit down.
あ、座って座ってください。
Ah, please take your seats.
ということでね、ファンサ歌っとったね。
So, you were singing 'Fanservice', weren't you?
あ、そうなんです。
Ah, that's right.
ファンサ歌っとったね。
You sang 'Fanservice'.
はい、ファンサ歌わせていただいて。
Yes, I had the chance to sing it.
はあ...めっちゃ緊張した...
Phew... I was so nervous...
緊張したの？
You were nervous?
歌い子なので、はい。
Well, I'm the singer, so yes.
でも、あの、先生から見たら...
But, from Teacher's perspective...
はい、どうでした？
Yes, how was I?
フブキ君は...
Fubuki-kun...
全然ファンサができてなかった！
didn't give enough fan service at all!
えー！？
What?!
なので、ちょっと反省したほうがいいと思う。
So, I think you should reflect on that a bit.
「好きにさせちゃうから」って言ったのに...なるほど、すみません。
Even though I said 'I'll make you love me'... I see, sorry.
まだ足りないから、ちょっと今ファンサしといたほうがいいと思う。
It's still not enough, so I think you should do some fan service now.
あ、いい、いいんですか？
Oh, is that okay?
何する？
What will you do?
じゃあやっぱり、やっぱライブと言ったら...
Well then, when it comes to live shows...
あの、コールアンドレスポンスじゃないですか、先生。
it's about the call and response, right, Teacher?
そうだなぁ。
That's true.
いいですか？
Is that okay?
いいよ。
It's okay.
皆さんもいいですか？やってくれますか？
Is everyone ready, too? Will you do it with me?
じゃあ、じゃあ、どうしようかな...えっと、じゃあ...
Well, well, what should I do... okay, then...
白上が「コンコンきーつね」って言うので、みんなで「ね！」って言ってください。
I'll say 'Kon kon kitsune' and everyone say 'Ne!' back.
「ね」だけ言う感じね。
So you just say 'Ne'.
そう、「ね」だけ言ってほしいです！みんな、いいですか！？
Right, I want you to just say 'Ne'! Everyone, ready?!
今日の生徒の皆さん、優しい。いいですね。じゃあ行きますよ。
Today's students are so kind. Great. Alright, here we go.
コンコンきーつね！
Kon kon kitsune!
ねー！
Ne!
おめでとう、おめでとう。
Congratulations, congratulations.
はい、ありがとうございます！
Yes, thank you very much!
これがファンサや。
That's what you call fan service.
これがファンサ...ああ、よかったです。
That's fan service... ah, I'm glad.
そやそや。
Exactly, exactly.
先生もどうですか？
How about you, Teacher?
え、先生もいいの？
Eh, is it okay if Teacher does it too?
先生もぜひやってほしい！
I definitely want Teacher to do it!
先生もいいの？やって？
Is it okay if I do it? Really?
どうします、先生。
What will you do, Teacher?
え、そしたら、じゃあ先生は、「ゆびゆび」って言いたいから...
Well then, Teacher wants to say 'Yubi yubi'...
え、先生が「ゆ」を担当するから...
so I'll be in charge of 'Yu'...
「び」、えっと「ゆ」「び」「ゆ」「び」ってことよ。分かった？
and you say 'bi'. So it's 'Yu' 'bi' 'Yu' 'bi'. Got it?
先生、いける？
Teacher, you ready?
降参するんじゃねえぞ、お前たち！ちゃんとやれよ！
Don't you dare give up, you lot! Do it properly!
皆さん、いけますよね！？いけるかー！？
Everyone, you can do it, right?! Are you ready?!
よしよしよし、行くぞ！
Good, good, good, here we go!
せーの！
One, two!
ゆ！
Yu!
び！
Bi!
ゆ！
Yu!
び！
Bi!
ああー！やったー！
Aaah! We did it!
満足満足、ありがとう、ありがとう。
I'm satisfied, satisfied. Thank you, thank you.
ということで、ホロハニフェス、始まりましたね！
And so, the Holo-Honey fest has begun!
始まっちゃったね！
It's really started!
始まりましたよ！マジでちょっと一曲目ファンサから歌わせていただきまして。
It has! We really kicked things off with 'Fanservice'.
いや、可愛かったぞ。
It was really cute.
ああ、よかったです。ありがとうございます。
Ah, I'm glad. Thank you very much.
先生の書き下ろし曲もさ、めちゃめちゃ可愛いじゃないですか。
The song Teacher wrote is also super cute, isn't it?
え、可愛いか？
Eh, is it cute?
MV見てみんな可愛かったですよね！？
Everyone was so cute in the music video, right?!
な、ありがとう、ありがとう。先生も頑張ったからな。
Yeah, thank you, thank you. Teacher worked hard too, you know.
生徒には負けられないからな。
I can't let the students beat me.
あ、流石ですね。
Ah, as expected.
ホロハニの唯一のね、先生ですからね。
You're the one and only teacher of Holo-Honey, after all.
そうだよ。先生だってね、制服着たかったんだからね！
That's right. Because even Teacher wanted to wear a uniform!
着たかったんだからな！そしたら白上だってちょっと先生やってみたかったり...
I really wanted to! Then Shirakami would also want to try being a teacher...
あ、本当に？
Oh, really?
なんかいいじゃない、ちょっと。
That sounds kinda nice, actually.
それは無理やな。でも、配役決まっちゃってるからな。
That's impossible. The roles have already been decided.
白上の先生もいいと思う人！いました！やったー！
Raise your hand if you think Teacher Shirakami would be good! There they are! Yay!
まあまあまあ、います、いますけど。でもコロちゃんの先生はいいと思うよ。
Well, well, there are some. But I think Teacher Koro-chan is good too.
お、本当ですか？
Oh, really?
なんかやってみる？じゃあ、先生みたいなことを。
Want to try something? Like doing something teacher-like.
あ、え、何ですかね？
Ah, e, what is it?
何だろう？
I wonder?
ちょっとじゃあ逆に、先生、生徒として、起立・注目・礼、やってみてくださいよ、すっきり気持ちよくなりたい。
Well then, conversely, Teacher, as a student, please do 'Stand, Attention, Bow', I want to feel refreshed.
あ、本当に？先生、おはようございます。
Oh, really? Good morning, teacher.
あ、おはようね。
Ah, good morning.
じゃあみんな、もう一回。「起立」って言うから、そしたら立つんだよ。
Okay everyone, one more time. I'll say 'Stand up', and then you stand up.
ほい。
Okay.
いい？
Ready?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、みんなおはよう。じゃあ先生に挨拶しようか。
Ah, good morning everyone. Shall we greet the teacher?
起立！
Stand up!
ごめんね、何回も。
Sorry, for doing this many times.
えー、気をつけ。
Ehh, Attention.
礼。
Bow.
違う違う違う違う違う！
No, no, no, no, no!
ふわぁって、あとどうだったっけ？わからなくなっちゃった。
Like 'fuwaa', and then how was it? I've forgotten.
「おはようございます」って、あ、そうだそうだ。
Saying 'Good morning'... Oh, that's right, that's right.
え、でもみんな「校長先生おはようございます」って言うから、もう一回言ってくれる？ごめんね。
Eh, but everyone will say 'Good morning, Principal', so can you say it again? Sorry.
校長先生？
Principal?
いや意味分からんこのMCどうなっとんやこれ。
No, I don't understand this MC, what's going on here.
行くよ。
Here we go.
おはようございます！
Good morning!
着席。
Sit down.
先生、おはようございます。
Teacher, good morning.
おはようございます。
Good morning.
戌神くん、そうこうしてる間にもう2分半経ってんだよ先生。
Inugami-kun, while we were doing that, 2 and a half minutes have already passed, Teacher.
すいません！すいません！すいません、ちょっとよくわからなくて。すいません！すいませんでした！
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry, I didn't really understand. Sorry! I'm sorry!
白上の方がやっぱ先生向いてますね皆さん。
Shirakami is more suited to be a teacher, everyone.
あ、確かに、そうだな。
Ah, indeed, that's true.
はい。ということでね、うん。
Yes. So anyway, yeah.
ちょっと、次の曲がなんと、実は、先生の曲が...
Wait, the next song is actually the teacher's song...
え、先生も歌っちゃうの！？
Eh, the teacher's going to sing too!?
そう、ラズマ！
Yes, Lazma!
先生の楽曲名何でしたっけ？
What was the teacher's song title again?
「可愛くてチェックメイト」だね。
'Cute Checkmate'.
可愛くてチェックメイト！
Cute Checkmate!
ということでちょっとね、先生、あ、可愛い子先にチェックしといたほうがいいんじゃね？
So, teacher, ah, shouldn't you check for cute girls first?
そうや、ちょっとこの会場に来てるみんなの中から可愛い子、ヤッホー！
That's right, let's find cute girls from everyone here, Yoo-hoo!
あ、ちょっと待って。
Ah, wait a second.
べっぴんさん、べっぴんさん、一人飛ばしてべっぴんさんやな！
Beautiful girl, beautiful girl, skip one and another beautiful girl!
ちょ、ちょ、ちょっと待って。あ、よく見たらべっぴんさんやな。
Wai- wai- wait a minute. Ah, looking closely, she's a beauty.
よく見たらって失礼じゃないですか！
Saying 'looking closely' is rude, isn't it!
みんな可愛いよ、みんな可愛いよ。
Everyone's cute, everyone's cute.
本当可愛いです、みんな。可愛いよ。
Everyone's really cute. You're cute.
一人飛ばして可愛いよ。
Skip one and you're cute.
やめろ、飛ばすな飛ばすな！
Stop it, don't skip, don't skip!
可愛いよ、可愛いよ。
You're cute, you're cute.
飛ばすな、飛ばすな！
Don't skip, don't skip!
あ、また位置入れ替わっちゃった。
Ah, the positions changed again.
右さんがね、左さんがね、左右に左右に...
The person on the right, the person on the left, to the right, to the left...
ということで、じゃあじゃあじゃあ、可愛くてチェックメイトいきますかね。
So, shall we go with 'Cute Checkmate'?
じゃあ最後にもう一回やっときますか、やっぱり。
Well, let's do it one last time, after all.
さぁよ。
Here we go.
最後の締めと言ったら起立、気をつけ...
For the final wrap-up, Stand up, Attention...
そうそうそう。
That's right.
皆様、皆様お待たせいたしました。
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting.
じゃあせーので行くよ、はい、せーの。
Let's go on three, ready, one, two...
せーの、起立！
Ready, Stand up!
気をつけ！
Attention!
礼！
Bow!
あ、キャ、礼！せーの...
Ah, ca-, Bow! Ready...
「Capture the Moment」！
'Capture the Moment'!
しっぽ振ってスカウト　しっぽ振ってスカウト
Wagging tail and scouting, wagging tail and scouting
可愛くもっとエンカウント　集まっちゃえば最強よ
Encounter more cutely, if we gather together, we're the strongest
ヤッホー！みんなをスカウトしに来たよ！
Yoo-hoo! I came to scout everyone!
断ったら許さねえよ！
I won't forgive you if you refuse!
文化祭が始まる　最大規模で行きたいの
The school festival begins, I want to do it on the largest scale
君も参加してよね　デートチケット無制限
You participate too, unlimited date tickets
校長先生もびっくり　キャスト足んない大焦り
Even the principal is surprised, lack of cast, in a huge panic
WAN WAN NIGHT SHOW
本番まではギリギリ　運営さんはキリキリ
Until the performance, it's down to the wire, management is feeling the pressure
スネちゃったなら大丈夫　テレフォンナンバーピーピーピー
If you get sulky, it's okay, telephone number pee-pee-pee
イケてる子用意して　もしもし私オーガナイザー
Prepare some cool kids, hello, I'm the organizer
可愛くてチェックメイト　吸い込まれたら
Cute Checkmate, once you're sucked in
J-J-J-J-衣装をゲット
G-G-G-G- get the outfit
お揃いでしょ？
We're matching, right?
パパもママも住んだなら　本番までお派手にね
Once Dad and Mom have moved in, let's keep it flashy until the performance
それくらい私も本気でやりたいの
That's how much I want to do it seriously
しっぽ振ってスカウト　しっぽ振ってスカウト
Wagging tail and scouting, wagging tail and scouting
可愛くもっとエンカウント　集まっちゃえば最強よ
Encounter more cutely, if we gather together, we're the strongest
はーい可愛い子発見！あっちにもいる！
Yes, found a cute girl! There's one over there too!
可愛い子が多すぎるだろ！
There are too many cute girls!
あの子もこっちもしんどいわ　どうしようもない焦燥感
That girl and this one are overwhelming, a feeling of helplessness and frustration
限界まではちょっと　これでもいいっちょ
Until the limit, a little bit... this is fine too
美味しいご飯食べたら　犬に金棒最強よ
If you eat delicious food, like giving a metal bat to a dog, the strongest
東西南北駆け回り　まだ見ぬあの子探し出せ
Running around in all directions, find that girl yet unseen
WAN WAN NIGHT SHOW
呼んだらどこでも駆けつけます　いい子がいたら教えてね
If you call, I'll rush anywhere, tell me if there's a good kid
甘んじちゃう　甘えちゃう
I'll just accept it, I'll just be pampered
…のばかしあい
...fox deception.
イケてる子がみつかった？
Did you find a cool kid?
もしもし私おバカなイヌ
Hello, I'm a silly dog.
可愛い子スカウト中
Scouting for cute ones!
超超超超超美少女決定だね
It's a super-duper-duper beautiful girl, for sure!
もしも私が死んだなら
If I were to die...
放送で飛び込んでね
...please jump into the broadcast.
それくらい私本気でやりたいの
That's how serious I want to be.
しっぽ振ってスカウト
Wagging my tail and scouting!
可愛いと思ったら歌おう
If you think it's cute, let's sing.
集まっちゃえばさ今日も
If we all gather today as well...
人生どうせは言いません
I won't say life is "anyway."
私に見合ってるよ
It really suits me.
一緒に怒られて
Getting scolded together...
一緒に大きくなって
...growing up together...
一緒に涙して
...crying together...
その分もっと笑った
...we laughed all the more for it.
みんな！見て見て！
Everyone! Look, look!
うちの可愛いアーニャちゃん！
My cute Anya-chan!
もうめちゃくちゃ可愛いでしょ！
She's just super duper cute, right?!
アーニャちゃん好き！好き好き好き！
I love Anya-chan! Love, love, love!
お姉ちゃんうるさい！
Big sister, you're noisy!
仲良しの姉妹で
As close sisters...
隠し事はなかった
...we had no secrets.
好きな人の話
Stories about people we like...
いつか聞きたいかも
...I might want to hear them someday.
突然どうしたの？
What happened all of a sudden?
うちら仲良しだけど
Even though we're close...
大人になるほどね
...the more we grow up...
秘密増やしていいの？
...is it okay for secrets to increase?
理想は映画の王子様
The ideal is a prince from a movie...
爽やかな王子様
...a refreshing prince.
どうしよう全然違うし
What should I do? He's totally different.
だけどいいの王子様
But it's okay, my prince.
ぶりっ子して
Acting cute,
ほっぺ染めて
cheeks blushing,
ポーズ決めて
striking a pose...
あてしよ
Look at me!
大好きだよ
I love you!
内緒だよ
It's a secret!
見つめ合って
Staring into each other's eyes,
可愛いねって
saying "you're cute."
苦手なこと
Things we're bad at,
得意なこと
things we're good at,
好みのとこ
things we like...
それぞれじゃん
they're all different.
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
嫌いなのよ
I really do hate you!
喧嘩してもずっと一緒だよね
But even if we fight, we're always together.
ヒラノくんですがお付き合いはしてます
He's just Hirano-kun, but we're dating.
イメージ真逆でもちゃんと仲良くしてね
Even if our images are opposite, please get along.
取られたくないからお化粧全て見せてよ
I don't want you taken, so show me all your makeup.
ホント楽しそうで私も嬉しくなった
You looked so happy, it made me happy too.
気になる人とかいないの？お姉ちゃんに教えて
No one you're interested in? Tell your big sis.
気分なの恋愛禁止今はダメ夢のため
It's my rule: no romance for now, for my dream.
ぶりっ子して
Acting cute,
ほっぺ染めて
cheeks blushing,
ポーズ決めて
striking a pose...
あてしよ
Look at me!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Staring into each other's eyes,
可愛いねって
saying "you're cute."
見てないとか見てないとか
Pretending not to look,
趣味だってさそれぞれじゃん
hobbies are different for everyone.
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
嫌いなの
仲直りもきっとすぐできる
We can surely make up quickly.
一つ屋根の下で
Under one roof,
明日も騒ごう
let's make a fuss tomorrow too.
ぶりっ子して
Acting cute,
ほっぺ染めて
cheeks blushing,
ポーズ決めて
striking a pose...
あてしよ
Look at me!
大好きだよ
I love you!
見つめ合って
Staring into each other's eyes,
可愛いねって
saying "you're cute."
苦手なこと
Things we're bad at,
得意なこと
things we're good at,
好みのとこ
things we like...
それぞれじゃん
they're all different.
嫌いだよ
I hate you!
仲直りも
Making up
きっとすぐできる
will surely be quick.
聞いてくれてありがとう！
Thanks for listening!
みんなありがとね！
Thanks everyone!
宣言しちゃいます
I'm making a declaration!
私たちテッペン目指して走ります
We're going to run and aim for the top!
勉強しちゃいます
I'm going to study!
すぐに忘れちゃうから
Because I'll forget it right away.
ララララ…
Lala lala...
チュ！チュ！
Chu! Chu!
アイドルその1！
Idol Rule #1!
アイドルその2！
Idol Rule #2!
アイドルその3！
Idol Rule #3!
アイドルその4！愛されよ
Idol Rule #4! Be loved!
朝練でお仕事ガクガクで
Morning practice makes my legs wobble during work
それでもな 子猫も手借りたい
Even so, I want to borrow a kitten's help
毎日チョーハード
Every day is super hard
（ヘイ！ヘイ！）
(Hey! Hey!)
ヘトヘト もう限界って
Exhausted, at my limit
アンチの言葉で 泣きたくなる日も
On days I want to cry from anti-fans' comments
周りのみんなに 置いてかれる日も
On days I'm left behind by everyone around me
しんどい時でも
Even when it's tough,
頑張ってて言ってくれたから
because you told me to keep going
全身全霊
With all my heart and soul,
声が届くまで 歌ってみせるよ
I'll keep singing until my voice reaches you
君からのエール 降るマジで頑張れちゃう今
Your cheers are falling, I can really work hard now
満員御礼 気合入って 友情一石二鳥
Full house, feeling pumped, friendship is two birds with one stone
アイドルその4！
Idol Rule #4!
アイドルその5！
Idol Rule #5!
アイドルその6！
Idol Rule #6!
アイドルですから 可愛くて！
Since I'm an idol, I'm cute!
怒って天罰 居残りか？
Angry divine punishment, staying after school?
そこ私の席なんですけど
That's my seat, though
占わない！ 最下位だ
I won't tell your fortune! You're last
しんどい時でも
Even when it's tough,
頑張ってて言ってくれたから
because you told me to keep going
全身全霊
With all my heart and soul,
声が届くまで 歌ってみせるよ
I'll keep singing until my voice reaches you
君の1番は誰？
Who is your number one?
言わずもがな分かるよね
You know it without me having to say
推し変厳禁 絶対！
Changing favorites is strictly forbidden!
私の推し活みててね
Watch my idol activities
アイドルその7！ いつしポジティブ
Idol Rule #7! Always positive
アイドルその8！ 時々あざとく
Idol Rule #8! Sometimes calculatingly cute
アイドルその9！ 挨拶マスト
Idol Rule #9! Greetings are a must
アイドルその10！
Idol Rule #10!
「ありがとう」
"Thank you"
君からのエール 降るマジで頑張れちゃう今
Your cheers are falling, I can really work hard now
満員御礼 気合入って 友情一石二鳥
Full house, feeling pumped, friendship is two birds with one stone
忘れないよ あの日の夢
I won't forget that day's dream
高み目指した目に刻めよ アイドル10ヶ条
Engrave the Idol 10 Commandments in your eyes that aimed for the heights
ヤッホー！
Yaho!
みんなに一番注目してもらいたい 桃鈴ねねです！
I want everyone to pay attention to me the most, I'm Momosuzu Nene!
みんなで「超絶可愛い！」って言ってくれたら
If you all say "Super cute!",
ねねのことだけ見ててくれる？
will you look only at me?
巡り会えた運命の推し
The fated favorite I met,
私の闇に輝く星
the star shining in my darkness
積んで積んでマウント取って
Stacking, stacking, taking the high ground,
経済回せ推し支援
support your favorite and keep the economy going
香水振った？
Put on perfume?
（大好き）
(I love you)
お手紙出そう
Let's send a letter
（大好き）
(I love you)
事務所通して
Through the agency
（大好き）
(I love you)
返事待ってる
Waiting for a reply
（大好き）
(I love you)
ねえここ（愛）散らかせて
Hey, let (love) scatter here
（大好き）
(I love you)
シンドい
It's tough
愛してるのファンだけど
I love you as a fan,
同じ人間を好きになっただけじゃん
but I just fell in love with another human being
誰かに向けたファンサービスに
Over fan service directed at someone else,
いつも嫉妬して落ち込んで
I'm always jealous and depressed
愛してるのファンだけど
I love you as a fan,
普通の恋と変わんないわけじゃん
but it's no different from a normal romance
イベントあるし すぐ会えるよね
There's an event, so we can meet soon
他の子へのファンサは ほどほどにしてよね
Keep the fan service for other girls to a minimum, okay?
勘違い匂わせは嫌い
I hate misleading hints
呟きすぎる奴は地雷
People who tweet too much are landmines
貢ぎ貢ぎバイトはフルで
Donating, donating, working part-time jobs full-time
持って持って寝入る推し色
Holding my favorite's color as I fall asleep
愛の大きさ
The size of love
（大好き）
(I love you)
プライベートバトル
Private battle
（大好き）
(I love you)
自信を持って
With confidence
（大好き）
(I love you)
ツイートしてね
Please tweet it
（大好き）
(I love you)
人気売れしけど
Even if you become popular
（大好き）
(I love you)
シンドい
It's tough
愛してるのファンだけど
I love you as a fan,
全部知ってるし 彼女みたいでしょ？
but I know everything, I'm like your girlfriend, right?
悟りの境地 遠のいちゃうし
The state of enlightenment fades away,
嫌になって 焦っちゃう
and I hate it and get impatient
愛してるのファンだけど
I love you as a fan,
ファンの子じゃない 道しるべになりたいの
but I want to be your guide, not just a fan
君守るし 幸せだし
I'll protect you, I'm happy,
一番近くがいい
and I want to be the closest
結婚しちゃいましょう
Let's get married
尊い 教え
Precious teachings
顔が良くてありがとう
Thank you for being so good-looking
私が生きる
I live because
理由をくれてありがとう
Thank you for giving me a reason
世界はあなた
The world revolves
中心に回ってる
Around you
愛しているの
I love you
文句ある？
Any complaints?
もう！ねねはこんなにみんなのこと考えてるのに！
Geez! Even though Nene is thinking about
everyone this much!
ほら！ペンライトの色が違う人がいるじゃん！
Look! There's someone whose
penlight is a different color!
みんな結婚してくれますかのお返事は？
What's everyone's answer to "Will you marry me?"
せーの！
Ready, go!
万丈の采は
With great fortune
景色を作ら
Creating the scenery
グラスを二つ
Two glasses
乾杯しよう
Let's have a toast
馬鹿にされたって
Even if people make fun of me
いいわ
That's fine
愛してるのファンだけど同じ人間を好きになっただけじゃん
I love you, I'm just a fan who fell for
another human being
誰かに向けたファンサにいつも嫉妬して落ち込んで
Always getting jealous and depressed over
fanservice aimed at others
愛してるのファンだけど普通の恋と変わんないわけじゃん
I love you, I'm just a fan, but it's no
different from a normal crush
イベントあるしすぐ会えるよね
There are events, so we can meet soon, right?
他の子のファンサはほどほどに
Keep the fanservice for other girls in moderation
してよね
Okay?
あ、ちょっと待って。ねねは副会長だから。
Oh, wait a sec. Nene is the vice president, after all.
なに急に？
What's with that all of a sudden?
え、ねねはこの学園の副会長。あなたは？
Well, Nene is the vice president of this academy.
And you?
んなたんはホロライブのアイドルの1年生なのかな。
I am a first-year idol of hololive, nanora.
かわいいー！
So cute!
え、副会長？
Eh, vice president?
かわいいー！
So cute!
かわいいのは副会長なのなら、さっきの同担拒否、めちゃくちゃかっこ…かっこいいじゃねえ、かわいかったんならよね。
If the vice president is cute, that "Doutan Kyohi"
earlier was super coo... not cool, but cute, nanora.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
さすが副会長だったんならよ。
As expected of the vice president, nanora.
ま、じゃあ副会長がちょっと仕切らせてもらうけど。
Well, then, as vice president,
I'll take charge for a bit.
なに急に？はい、どうぞ。
What's with that all of a sudden? Yes, go ahead.
自己紹介、まずしてもらっていいかな？1年生の方から。
Could you start with an introduction?
From the first-year.
あ、はい、わかりました。えーと、初めまして。アイドル1年生の姫森ルーナなのかな。皆さんよろしくお願いいたします。
Ah, yes, I understand. Um, nice to meet you.
I am a first-year idol, Himemori Luna, nanora.
Pleased to meet you all.
んならーって滑らなくてよかったんなら？
It was good I didn't mess up
the "nanora," right?
んならーって。
"Nanora."
アイドルまだ1年生なんで、ちょっと副会長の前だと、まだちょっとまだ、慣れないんで。
Since I'm still a first-year idol, I'm still a bit,
well, not used to being in front of the vice president.
うん、ではどうぞ。
Yes, then go ahead.
じゃあ私副会長、みんなの心のっていう部分があるから、その後に「エナジードリンク」で返してください。
Now, as vice president, I'll say
"Everyone's heart's..." and you respond
with "Energy Drink!"
行きますよ。ホロライブ5期生、みんなの心の？
Here we go. Hololive 5th Gen,
everyone's heart's...?
エナジードリンク！
Energy Drink!
はい、よきー！
Yes, good!
んなら、ねねたちが一番可愛いじゃない？
Then, aren't we the cutest?
おい、おい、おい、ちょっと待ってほしいんなら。ちょっとさっきおかゆと二人で歌ったアイドル10ヶ条もかわいかったんならよね。
Hey, hey, hey, hold on a sec, nanora.
"Idol 10-kajou," which I sang earlier with Okayu,
was also cute, nanora.
ほら！もっと声出せるだろう！
See! You can cheer louder than that!
すごいよかったよ。
It was really good.
んな、よかった。かわいかったよかったんならよ。
Na, that's good. It was cute and good, nanora.
え、ちょっと、もうちょっと近づいてよ。
Hey, come a bit closer.
近いんなら。
That's close, nanora.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
近すぎ？
Too close?
うん、これぐらい。あ、ちょっと近いかも。
Yeah, about this much. Oh, might be a bit close.
あ、ちょっと近い、ちょっと近いすぎたんなら。
Oh, a bit close, it's a bit too close, nanora.
かわいいー！んならー！素晴らしいー！
Cute! Nanora! Wonderful!
今日はね、なんと韓国、インドネシアで
Today, we're having live viewings in
Korea and Indonesia,
ライブビューイング中でもあるので、
so please post your impressions of this live
ぜひこちらのライブの感想をハッシュタグ
on social media with the hashtag
「#hololivefesEXPO24_DAY2」で SNSにアップしてください。
#hololivefesEXPO24_DAY2.
お願いしますんならー！
Please do, nanora!
じゃあ、ちょっとあの、いつものね、ペンライト、やっぱりやりたいよね。
Well then, let's do the usual penlight thing.
やりたいんならー！
I want to do it, nanora!
じゃあまず、ルーナ姫の、ピンクにみんな、ライトピンクに！
First, everyone change to Princess Luna's color,
pink! Light pink!
3, 2...
1... イェーイ！みんなピンクにしてー！
1... Yay! Everyone, turn it pink!
うわ〜！お〜すごい！
Whoa~! Oh, amazing!
かわいい〜！
So cute~!
お〜！あれ、いい？なんかウェーブとかしちゃう？
Oh~! Is that good? Should we do a wave or something?
ウェーブ？あ？お？ウェーブ好きなの？
Wave? Ah? Oh? Do you like waves?
よし、じゃあこっちからみんな、ウェーーーーブ！
Alright! Then from this side, everyone, wave~!
え、じゃみんな、次はオレンジに切り替えて！
Alright everyone, next switch to orange!
オレンジなのら！
Orange nanora!
3, 2, 1... こっちから！
3, 2, 1... From this side!
ウェーーーーブ！
Wave~!
いいねー！めっちゃ綺麗なのらなー！
Nice! It's so beautiful!
ありがとーーー！
Thank you~!
あれもやろうぜ！
Let's do that too!
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
じゃあ声出し！
Then, voice check!
声出し行くぞ！男子ーーー！
Let's go, voice check! Boys~!
男子ーーー！
Boys~!
よし行くぞ、女子ーーー！
Alright, let's go, girls~!
もっといけるだろ！
You can do better!
女子！みんな心は女子やろ！？
Girls! Everyone's heart is a girl, right?!
もう一回いこう、もう一回！せーの！
One more time, one more time! Ready...!
女子ーーー！
Girls~!
うっそーい女子！
Lots of girls!
そして、そんなの関係なく！
And, regardless of all that!
全員ーーー！
Everyone~!
そして！
And!
ここからは！
From here!
なんと！
What!
無料パート終了のお知らせなのらー！
It's an announcement that the free part is ending nanora!
なので、概要欄からぜひチケットを買ってみんな見てください！
So, please buy a ticket from the description and watch everyone!
え、そして今ですね、ちょっと運営さんの方からご訂正がありまして...
And, right now, I have a correction from the management...
韓国とインドネシアのライブビューイングリンクは、ありませんでした！
The live streaming links for Korea and Indonesia... do not exist!
すみませんでしたーーー！
We are very sorry!
では、次の歌に繋げていくのらね！
Well then, let's lead into the next song nanora!
行こう！
Let's go!
せーの、Capture the Moment!
Ready... Capture the Moment!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended. Thank you for watching!